A database is a piece of software that runs on a computer,
数据库是运行在电脑上的一款软件
and it's subject to the same limitations as all software.
和所有软件一样 它也有局限性
It can only process as much information as the hardware is capable of handling.
它只能在硬件处理性能范围内处理信息
The way to make a query run faster,
提升查询运行速度的一个办法
is to reduce the number of calculations that need to be performed.
是减少需要进行的计算的数量
To do this, you'll need some understanding of how SQL actually makes those calculations.
为此 你需要了解一点 SQL 实际如何进行这些计算
First, let's address some of
首先 我们来了解一下哪些主要因素
the high level things that will affect
将影响一项给定的查询
the number of calculations a given query will make.
需要进行的计算的数量
Table size is incredibly important.
毋庸置疑 表格大小是重要因素
If your query hits one or more tables with millions of rows or more,
如果查询设计包含几百万列甚至更多
it could affect performance.
这将会影响性能
If your query joins two tables,
如果查询需要合并两张表格
in a way that substantially increases the row count of the result set,
会大大增加结果集的列数
your query is likely to be slow.
查询将可能变慢
And finally, aggregations can dramatically impact query runtime.
最后 聚合会很大程度上影响查询运行时间
Combining multiple rows to produce
合并若干列产生
a result requires more computation than simply retrieving those rows.
一项结果比单纯查询这些列需要进行更多的计算
In particular, count distinct takes a very long time compared to the regular count,
尤其是 去重以后再计数相比常规计数要花费更多时间
because it must check all rows against one another for duplicate values.
因为它需要检查对所有列进行交叉验证以获得重复值
Query runtime is also dependent on some things that you really
查询运行时间也依赖于不受你控制的且与
can't control that are related to the database itself.
数据库本身有关的一些因素
The more queries running concurrently on a database,
数据库要同时运行的查询越多
the more the database must process at a given time,
数据库就要在指定时间内处理的数据越多
and the slower everything will run.
所有运行就会越慢
It can be especially bad if others are running
更坏的情况是 其他人在运行
particularly resource intensive queries
尤其是资源密集型查询
that fulfill some of the criteria that we just went over.
而这些查询符合我们提到的标准
Also, different databases vary in speed for a given task.
同时 不同数据库在执行给定任务时表现不同
For example, Postgres is optimized to read and write new rows quickly,
例如 Postgres 在快速读写新列方面有优势
while Redshift is optimized to perform fast aggregations.
而 Redshift 在执行快速聚合方面表现更好
This is something you probably can't control, but,
这些就是你很可能无法控制的因素 但是
if you know the system you're using,
如果你了解你正在使用的系统
you can work within its bounds to make your queries more efficient.
你可以在系统性能范围内更高效地执行查询
For now, let's ignore the things that you
我们暂且忽略不受控制的因素
can't control and work on the things that you can.
而关注我们可以控制的因素